What did I steal? What are you talking about?
내가 무엇을 훔쳤나요? 무슨 소리를 하는 걸까요?
my novel
내 소설
Don't lie shamelessly in front of me
내 앞에서 뻔뻔하게 거짓말하지 마
I want to make the truth known to the world
진실을 세상에 알리고 싶다
Why are you so annoying Soon Ae?
순애야 왜이렇게 짜증나?
Keep making trouble
계속 문제를 일으키세요
Be careful to end up like your sister Shun Ai
언니 슌아이처럼 되지 않도록 조심하세요
What puzzles me most during this time
이 시간 동안 나를 가장 당황하게 만드는 것은 무엇입니까?
That's the sentence
그 문장이에요
"Women who read are dangerous"
"읽는 여자는 위험하다"
Li Zhuying does have a book at hand
Li Zhuying은 손에 책을 가지고 있습니다.
The reason why Li Jingai went to that abandoned house
이정개이가 그 버려진 집에 간 이유
It’s to send Baek Yoo-seop away
백유섭을 보내기 위해서다
The only thing I need from Lee Joo Young
이주영한테 딱 필요한 건
It turns out to be a book
책으로 나오네요
The victims really have something in common
피해자들에겐 공통점이 있다
That's the book in their hands
그게 그 사람들 손에 있는 책이야
Maybe this is a warning
어쩌면 이건 경고일지도 몰라
I once wanted a woman who likes to read books
한때는 책 읽는 걸 좋아하는 여자를 원했는데
Why do they always look like that?
왜 그들은 항상 그렇게 보일까요?
As if I am such a unique existence
마치 내가 이렇게 독특한 존재인 것처럼
It’s really unpleasant to look at
보기에 정말 안쓰럽다
What are you doing
뭐하세요
It seems like you won't be able to tie the rope for a while.
당분간은 밧줄을 묶을 수 없을 것 같습니다.
Does that hand hurt?
그 손이 아프니?
It's all because you always like to drink
다 네가 늘 술을 좋아해서 그런 거야
will never get better
결코 나아지지 않을 것이다
Cases that happened in the village
마을에서 일어난 사건들
I saw the murderer
나는 살인자를 보았다
I saw him kill someone with my own eyes
나는 그가 누군가를 죽이는 것을 내 눈으로 보았다
The murderer is my brother
살인자는 내 동생이야
alright
괜찮은
This is really good stuff, right?
이거 정말 좋은 물건이군요, 그렇죠?
Oh, of course
오 당연하지
If I had taken good care of it, let alone a hundred years.
내가 잘 돌봤다면 백년은 고사하고.
It won't be a problem even if it lasts two hundred years.
200년이 지나도 문제가 되지 않습니다.
Well, that's how it should be
글쎄, 그래야지
I plan to give it to my grandson to wear in the future.
앞으로도 손자에게 입혀주려고 합니다.
"Grandson" Yanyu
"손자" 얀유
Has Yanyu already talked about his marriage partner?
Yanyu가 이미 그의 결혼 파트너에 대해 이야기했습니까?
Could it be that I got on the bus first and paid for the ticket later?
혹시 제가 버스를 먼저 타고 나중에 표값을 지불한 것이 아닐까요?
You really are too
너도 정말 그렇지
If you talk nonsense, something will happen.
말도 안 되는 소리를 하면 무슨 일이 일어날 것이다.
Otherwise
그렇지 않으면
that
저것
I had a dream not long ago
얼마전에 꿈을 꿨어요
I'm walking in a thick fog
짙은 안개 속을 걷고 있어
You know there is an old bridge in the back mountain, right?
뒷산에 오래된 다리가 있는 거 아시죠?
As a result, on the old bridge
결과적으로 오래된 다리에서
But suddenly a tiger that big appeared
그런데 갑자기 그렇게 큰 호랑이가 나타났어요
But it obediently let me hold it in my arms
하지만 순순히 품에 안게 해주었어
Isn't this a great dream?
정말 좋은 꿈이지 않나요?
I just think this dream is related to my grandson
그냥 이 꿈이 내 손자와 관련이 있는 것 같아요
I plan to buy it first and prepare it.
먼저 구매해서 준비할 생각이에요.
Although I don’t know when it will be
비록 그것이 언제가 될지는 모르지만
But you should have a very smart grandson
하지만 넌 아주 똑똑한 손자를 가져야 해
I'm here to commemorate our first meeting
우리의 첫 만남을 기념하기 위해 왔습니다
Just bought this
방금 이걸 샀어요
I really don’t know when he and I will meet in person.
그 사람과 내가 언제 직접 만날지는 정말 모르겠어요.
Really curious
정말 궁금하다
Wait, please wait.
잠깐만 기다려 주세요.
Wait a moment
잠깐만요
This is a misunderstanding
이것은 오해입니다
Things are not what Detective Bai thought
상황은 바이 형사가 생각한 것과 다릅니다
Get out of the way or you'll get hurt
비켜라 그렇지 않으면 다칠 것이다
listen to me
내 말 좀 들어봐
Didn't I explain it to you just now?
내가 지금 설명하지 않았나요?
Ask me to find your person
당신의 사람을 찾아달라고 부탁하세요
How could you possibly kill someone? This is outrageous.
어떻게 사람을 죽일 수 있습니까? 이것은 터무니없는 일입니다.
I told you to get out of the way quickly
빨리 나가라고 했잖아
Yunying, it's okay
윤영아, 괜찮아
It's fine
괜찮아
Please let me talk to her
내가 그녀와 얘기할 수 있게 해주세요
during my absence
내가 없는 동안
She has to live her own life
그녀는 자신의 삶을 살아야 한다
she is my family
그녀는 내 가족이야
You are limited to three minutes to finish
완료 시간은 3분으로 제한되어 있습니다.
Just trust me
그냥 나를 믿어
Of course, what's there to ask?
물론, 무엇을 물어볼 것이 있습니까?
when i arrived
내가 도착했을 때
he has been killed
그는 살해당했습니다
Maybe to save your mother
어쩌면 엄마를 구하기 위해서일지도 몰라
Just fight the prisoner alone.
그냥 죄수와 혼자 싸우세요.
then what should i do
그럼 난 어떻게 해야 해?
What should I do
어떻게 해야 하나요?
I'll be back soon. Don't worry too much.
곧 돌아올테니 너무 걱정하지 마세요.
You go and stay with your aunt first.
너는 가서 먼저 이모 집에 있어라.
Gotta keep her in a safe place as much as possible
최대한 안전한 곳에 보관해야 해요
stay with other people
다른 사람들과 함께 있어라
besides
게다가
can you drive
운전할 수 있어?
Do you know how to drive?
운전하는 법을 아시나요?
Why are you asking this?
왜 이런 걸 묻는 거죠?
Won't you be back soon?
곧 돌아오지 않을래?
Then why are you asking me this now?
그럼 왜 지금 나한테 이런 걸 묻는 겁니까?
just in case
혹시라도
if it were me
나라면
Nothing will happen
아무것도 안 일어날거야
Didn't I tell you about the future I want?
내가 원하는 미래에 대해 말하지 않았나요?
anyway
그래도
I will wait for your return at our home
우리 집에서 당신이 돌아올 때까지 기다릴게요
i will be alone
나는 혼자 있을 것이다
Still very scared
그래도 많이 무서워
So you have to come back quickly
그러니까 빨리 돌아와야 해
don't get hurt
상처받지 마세요
knew
알고 있었다
I will definitely do it
꼭 할게요
Really, this guy is really shameless.
사실 이 사람은 정말 뻔뻔한 사람이에요.
Forget it, the evidence is conclusive anyway.
잊어 버리세요. 어쨌든 증거는 결정적입니다.
No need to waste time waiting for him to confess
그 사람이 고백할 때까지 기다리느라 시간을 낭비할 필요가 없어요
Organize the information you currently have
현재 가지고 있는 정보를 정리해보세요
Send him there at dawn tomorrow morning
내일 아침 새벽에 그를 그곳으로 보내세요
- Yes Yes
- 예 예
Oh my god, this trouble is finally over.
맙소사, 드디어 이 문제가 끝났습니다.
Hey, what's going on?
이봐 무슨 일이야?
Damn it, I'm going crazy
젠장, 미칠 것 같아
Didn’t you say that the prisoner has been arrested?
죄수가 체포됐다고 하지 않았나요?
Didn't you say that catching that guy would close the case?
그 사람을 잡으면 사건이 종결된다고 하지 않았나요?
How could this happen again?
어떻게 이런 일이 다시 일어날 수 있습니까?
Why is it my daughter again?
왜 또 내 딸이야?
If anything happens to her
그녀에게 무슨 일이 생기면
How are you going to say it responsibly?
어떻게 책임감있게 말할 건가요?
- Dad, stop talking. - It's true.
- 아빠, 얘기하지 마세요 - 사실이에요
It’s not enough to take away our Jing Ai’s life
우리 징아이의 생명을 앗아가는 것만으로는 충분하지 않습니다
If that guy is caught by me
그 사람이 나한테 잡히면
I will definitely cut him into pieces
나는 그를 확실히 조각조각 잘라버릴 것이다
What should I do with my baby girl?
내 딸아이를 어떻게 해야 합니까?
Oh my god
맙소사
Soon Ae
순애
We are in the body of classmate Li Shunai
우리는 동급생 Li Shunai의 몸에 있습니다
Find the matchbox at Fengfeng Tea House
Fengfeng Tea House에서 성냥갑 찾기
There is also a note inside
안에 메모도 있어요
Not only did he write "Women who read are dangerous"
그는 "읽는 여자는 위험하다"라고 썼을 뿐만 아니라
Even the handwriting is the same, I'm sure
글씨체도 똑같을 거라 확신해요
This is exactly the same as what was written on the note before
이전에 메모에 적힌 내용과 똑같습니다.
Gao Meishu is not a prisoner but a witness
가오메이슈는 죄수가 아니라 증인이다
The prisoner is male
죄수는 남자다
The only person who knows what the prisoner looks like
죄수의 생김새를 아는 유일한 사람
That's Go Mi-sook
고미숙이에요
I think the guy in the abandoned house is the real murderer
내 생각엔 버려진 집에 있던 남자가 진짜 살인자인 것 같아
good
좋은
As soon as classmate Li Shunai woke up,
동급생 리 슈나이가 깨어나자마자,
Just contact me right away
그냥 바로 연락주세요
good
좋은
Yoon Haejun
윤해준
From the evening of the 16th to the early morning of the 17th
16일 저녁부터 17일 이른 아침까지
That is to say
즉 말하자면
Li Zhuying
리 주잉
The time when Li Jingai was killed
이정개(Li Jingai)가 살해된 시간
Where are you and what are you doing?
당신은 어디에 있고 무엇을 하고 있나요?
you
너
Is there a problem
문제가 있습니까
who is the prisoner
죄수는 누구입니까?
Why did you come to ask me this question?
왜 나에게 이런 질문을 하러 왔나요?
Another person was killed
또 다른 사람이 사망했습니다.
This time it's a male student
이번엔 남학생이다
Same school and grade as you
당신과 같은 학교, 같은 학년
A good boy died in an abandoned house
착한 소년이 버려진 집에서 죽었습니다
Why
왜
Because if he hadn’t died, it would have been Lee Soon Ae
죽지 않았다면 이순애였을 테니까.
What are you talking about
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요
Shun Ai almost died at the hands of the real murderer
순아이는 진짜 살인자의 손에 죽을 뻔했다
He died to save Soon Ae
순애를 구하기 위해 죽었다.
He died because of you
그 사람 너 때문에 죽었어
How could it be because of me?
어떻게 나 때문에 그럴 수가 있지?
If only you had called the police from the beginning
처음부터 경찰에 신고했더라면
If you hadn't lied
거짓말을 하지 않았다면
Just frame someone
그냥 누군가를 모함하세요
If you make everyone's work in vain
모든 사람의 수고를 헛되게 하면
That won't happen today
오늘은 그런 일 없을 거야
Although I don’t know who you listened to and what
누구의 말을 듣고 무엇을 들었는지는 모르겠지만
but i don't know anything
하지만 난 아무것도 몰라
Stop talking nonsense and tell me quickly.
헛소리 그만하고 빨리 말해.
Who is the prisoner?
죄수는 누구입니까?
Why are you telling me what to do?
왜 나에게 무엇을 해야할지 말하는거야?
who are you
누구세요
He always appears in front of me and gets in my way
그 사람은 언제나 내 앞에 나타나서 내 앞을 가로막는다.
Anyway, your plan
아무튼 네 계획은
It's finished, Go Mi-sook
끝났어요 고미숙님
The Chinese teacher was arrested
중국어 교사가 체포됐다
What did you say
뭐라고 하셨나요
He might have to take all the blame
그 사람이 모든 책임을 져야 할 수도 있어요
what do you mean
무슨 뜻이에요
Everything is screwed up
모든 게 망가졌어
How could it be possible that Gao Minxiu, who was arrested by the police, committed murder?
경찰에 체포된 가오민슈가 살인을 저질렀다는 게 어떻게 가능했을까요?
The police need a new prisoner anyway
경찰은 어쨌든 새로운 죄수가 필요하다
It turns out that person happened to be
알고 보니 그 사람이 그랬다.
I know the reason why you did this Gao Meishu
나는 당신이 왜 이런 짓을 했는지 알고 있습니다. Gao Meishu
But it's wrong to do this
하지만 이렇게 하는 것은 잘못이다
Too many people are in danger
위험에 처한 사람이 너무 많아
If you need another way I will help you
다른 방법이 필요하면 내가 도와줄게
So please help me be beautiful once
그러니 한 번만 예뻐지도록 도와주세요.
As long as you are willing to tell me who the prisoner is
죄수가 누구인지 말해 줄 의향이 있는 한
let me go
나를 보내줘
I don't need your help
네 도움은 필요 없어
I know nothing. You can leave.
난 아무것도 몰라요. 떠나셔도 됩니다.
I already know that you appeared in Li Jingai's
이정가에 출연하신 걸 이미 알고 있어요
Crime scene
범죄 현장
I'm asking about your previous whereabouts
이전 행적을 묻고 있어요
Where were you and what were you doing at that time?
당신은 그 당시 어디에 있었고 무엇을 하고 있었나요?
I was also with Liu Fanlong at that time
나도 그때 Liu Fanlong과 함께 있었어
Because he called me
그 사람이 나한테 전화했으니까
At that time too
그 때에도
She is dead teacher
그 사람은 죽었어 선생님
she is dead
그녀는 죽었다
It finally became like this
드디어 이렇게 됐네요
You were looking at Lee Joo Young's body
이주영의 몸을 보고 있었다
He was very scared when he came to me
그 사람은 나에게 왔을 때 매우 무서웠어요
Don't dare tell the police
감히 경찰에 말하지 마세요
Isn't she a communist?
그 사람은 공산주의자 아닌가요?
That way everyone will know
그러면 다들 알겠지
I saw her but didn't report it
그 사람 봤지만 신고는 안 했어
The reason why he is so scared
그 사람이 겁이 많은 이유
Get involved with teacher Li Zhuying
Li Zhuying 선생님과 함께 참여하세요
I think you should also know the reason very well
그 이유도 잘 아셔야 할 것 같아요
After all, your nephew is his classmate
결국, 당신의 조카는 그의 동급생입니다
if you now
만약 당신이 지금
I plan to blame all this on Liu Fanlong
나는 이 모든 것을 Liu Fanlong에게 비난할 계획이다
You're asking for my alibi.
당신은 내 알리바이를 요구하고 있습니다.
I just answered honestly
난 그냥 솔직하게 대답했어
Liu Fanlong is not a prisoner
Liu Fanlong은 죄수가 아닙니다
You can tell just by looking at the handwriting
손글씨만 봐도 알 수 있죠
And the same applies to my case
그리고 내 경우에도 마찬가지야
You will know better when you go to school
학교에 가보면 더 잘 알 것이다.
Exam papers and homework during this period
이 기간 동안의 시험지와 숙제
You can’t deceive people by writing so many things.
글을 너무 많이 써서 사람을 속일 수는 없습니다.
So what is this
그래서 이것은 무엇입니까?
I found this in your pocket
네 주머니에서 이걸 찾았어
That's what I picked up
그게 내가 집어온 거야
Are you kidding me now?
지금 장난하는 거야?
I know it's all mixed up now
지금은 모든 게 뒤죽박죽인 걸 알아
But there are many ways to confirm
하지만 확인하는 방법은 여러 가지가 있습니다
my handwriting
내 손글씨
And classmate Li Shunai
그리고 동급생 리 슈나이
You can wait until she wakes up and listen to what she has to say
그녀가 깨어날 때까지 기다렸다가 그녀가 하는 말을 들어보세요.
See who she is trying to escape from
그녀가 누구에게서 탈출하려고 하는지 확인하세요
And why did Liu Fanlong have to die there?
그리고 Liu Fanlong은 왜 그곳에서 죽어야 했습니까?
I'm also extremely curious
저도 굉장히 궁금합니다
Every time I meet you during this time
이 시간에 널 만날 때마다
Everyone thinks you are suspicious
다들 당신이 의심스럽다고 생각해요
So I plan to take this opportunity to find out
그래서 이번 기회에 알아보려고 합니다
Why do I find you at the scene every time something happens?
왜 무슨 일이 있을 때마다 현장에서 당신을 발견하는 걸까요?
You can look forward to it
기대하셔도 좋습니다
Because you won’t be able to escape the law this time
이번엔 법에서 벗어날 수 없으니까
This may sound outrageous
터무니없는 소리로 들릴 수도 있지만
But I think you
하지만 내 생각엔 당신이
Like someone who came here intentionally to save me
날 구해주려고 일부러 여기 온 사람처럼
Really thank you very much
정말 고마워요
The money was originally intended to be left to Shun Ai for tuition.
그 돈은 원래 슌아이에게 수업료로 남겨두려고 했었다.
Soon Ae is the teacher
순애 선생님이에요
teacher
선생님
The prisoner is catching up
죄수가 따라잡고 있다
Wake up, Fan Long
일어나세요, 팬롱님
anyway
그래도
I will wait for your return at our home
우리 집에서 당신이 돌아올 때까지 기다릴게요
So you have to come back quickly
그러니까 빨리 돌아와야 해
don't get hurt
상처받지 마세요
I will definitely do it
꼭 할게요
But who is he?
그런데 그는 누구입니까?
Why have you been crying since last night?
어젯밤부터 왜 울었어?
He's the one who went up to our rooftop
우리 옥상에 올라간 사람이에요
What did you say
뭐라고 하셨나요
Then that brat
그럼 그 새끼
Oh, please let him go
아, 그 사람 좀 보내주세요
He worked so hard because of us
우리 때문에 너무 고생했어요
Even though he did nothing wrong, he was still arrested by the police.
그는 아무 잘못도 하지 않았는데도 경찰에 체포됐다.
For the sake of Shun Ai
슌아이를 위해서
He closed his mouth tightly and said nothing.
그는 입을 굳게 다물고 아무 말도 하지 않았다.
It looks like he hasn't eaten all day
하루종일 밥도 안 먹은 것 같네
Why is he hungry?
왜 배가 고프나요?
Why are you hungry for Shun Ai?
왜 Shun Ai에 대해 배가 고프나요?
The doctor said Soon Ae was just too shocked
의사는 순애가 너무 충격을 받았다고 하더군요
There's nothing wrong with it
아무 문제 없어요
She'll wake up soon
그 사람은 곧 깨어날 거야
Eat quickly
빨리 먹어
Really
정말
I feel like I can't eat it
왠지 못 먹을 것 같은 느낌
Soon Ae is still lying in the hospital bed
순애는 아직도 병원 침대에 누워있습니다
How scared do you feel?
얼마나 두렵습니까?
How cruel
얼마나 잔인한가
This will keep her from waking up
이렇게 하면 그녀가 깨어나지 못하게 될 것입니다
That bastard
그 새끼
catch the culprit
범인을 잡아라
I will never spare that guy
난 그 사람 절대 아끼지 않을 거야
Then you need to eat more
그럼 더 먹어야지
How can a man be so thin and frail?
사람이 어떻게 그렇게 마르고 연약할 수 있나요?
hurry up
서둘러요
Open your mouth
입을 열
Open your mouth quickly
빨리 입을 벌려
Hurry up and eat it like this
빨리 이대로 먹어
Eat
먹다
Hurry up and pick up the chopsticks
빨리 젓가락을 집으세요
Come out
나오다
Tell me
말해 주세요
what happened
무슨 일이에요
Your ID card, resume, teacher qualification certificate
신분증, 이력서, 교원 자격증
It's all fake
다 가짜야
What exactly is going on
정확히 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
just in case
혹시라도
Include previous workplaces and residential addresses
이전 직장 및 거주지 주소 포함
I've checked all the information you left.
남겨주신 정보를 모두 확인했습니다.
But there is no evidence to prove your existence
하지만 당신의 존재를 증명할 증거는 없습니다
Not only that, you weren't even born
게다가 넌 태어나지도 않았어
Do you know what this means?
이것이 무엇을 의미하는지 아십니까?
Do you know this is a more dangerous situation than killing someone?
이것이 사람을 죽이는 것보다 더 위험한 상황이라는 것을 알고 계십니까?
Answer truthfully when I give you the chance.
기회를 줄 때 솔직하게 대답해 주세요.
I'm trying to bear with you and Bai Yunying
나는 당신과 Bai Yunying을 참으려고 노력하고 있습니다
The urge to arrest them together as spies
함께 간첩으로 체포하고 싶은 충동
I want to have a good chat with you
나는 당신과 좋은 대화를 나누고 싶습니다
Just because of the favor I owe you
내가 당신에게 빚진 호의 때문에
Uncle, you are wrong
삼촌, 당신은 틀렸어요
Because you never came to see me while I was in the hospital
내가 병원에 ​​있는 동안 당신은 한 번도 나를 보러 오지 않았기 때문에
so you may not know
그래서 당신은 모를 수도 있어요
If it weren’t for that teacher, my brother and I would
그 선생님 아니었으면 나와 내 동생은
don't know what will happen
무슨 일이 일어날지 몰라
He comes to our ward every day and pats our shoulders
매일 우리 병동에 찾아와 어깨를 두드려 주시는 분
He is like our guardian
그는 우리의 보호자와 같습니다
The only one for our brothers
우리 형제들을 위한 유일한 것
guardian
보호자
Why don't you stand up for my stupid uncle?
내 멍청한 삼촌을 위해 일어서지 그래?
to take care of my poor nephews
가난한 조카들을 돌보기 위해
It's this favor
바로 이 호의다
make me put these ridiculous things
이런 말도 안되는 것들을 넣게 해주세요
And your suspicious behavior that no need to be asked anymore
그리고 더 이상 물어볼 필요도 없는 너의 수상한 행동
Brought to you
당신에게 가져왔습니다
so hurry up
그러니 서둘러
Can you give me an explanation that I can accept?
제가 받아들일 수 있는 설명을 해주실 수 있나요?
if i said
내가 말했다면
would you believe it
당신은 그것을 믿을 것인가?
if i put everything
내가 모든 걸 다 넣으면
All confess truthfully
다들 솔직하게 고백해
Will you believe me
나를 믿으시겠어요?
What
무엇
I have something to show you
보여드릴 게 있어요
besides
게다가
Although I never thought that you would owe me a favor
당신이 나에게 은혜를 입게 될 줄은 꿈에도 몰랐지만
But if you really think so, just this once
하지만 정말로 그렇게 생각한다면 이번 한 번만이라도
can you do me one last favor
마지막 부탁 하나만 들어줄 수 있어?
Chairman Yin Bingqiu
인빙추 회장
Help me bring him to my house
그를 우리 집으로 데려갈 수 있게 도와주세요
It's now
지금이야
what is happening
무슨 일이야?
This is it
이거 야
Oops
이런
- Come over here, please. - Okay.
- 이리로 와주세요 - 알았어
- Let's go. - Come up.
- 가자 - 올라와
what are these
이것들은 무엇입니까?
How could this happen?
어떻게 이런 일이 일어날 수 있습니까?
Why is news from 1988 here?
1988년 뉴스가 여기에 있는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Why are the notes I wrote here?
내가 쓴 메모가 왜 여기에 있지?
I think you'll have to see it with your own eyes to believe it.
직접 눈으로 확인해봐야 믿을 수 있을 것 같아요.
that is
그건
The fact that I'm from the future
내가 미래에서 왔다는 사실
Although I came from a very far away time
아주 먼 옛날에서 왔지만
But the relationship between us is not that far away
하지만 우리 사이의 관계는 그리 멀지 않아요
my dad's dad
우리 아빠의 아빠
That’s Chairman Yoon Byeong-qiu
바로 윤병규 회장이다.
Your nephew Baek Hee-seop's future daughter
조카 백희섭 미래의 딸
It’s Baek Yunying who lives with me
나랑 같이 사는 백윤잉이야
You must have seen it many times
여러번 보셨을 텐데요
In other words, you are in a time machine
즉, 당신은 타임머신 안에 있는 것이다.
Did you come here?
여기 오셨나요?
Yes
예
That is to say, these cases that happened here
즉, 여기서 일어난 사건들은
Because we caught the wrong culprit
범인을 잘못 잡았으니까
So it will lead to your death
그래서 그것은 당신의 죽음으로 이어질 것입니다
So you came here to catch the real culprit yourself
그래서 진짜 범인을 직접 잡으러 여기까지 오셨군요
do you mean this
이 말인가요?
Yes
예
Sorry, Chairman, let's go
죄송합니다 위원장님, 가세요
It's all my fault for believing this lunatic's words
이 미친놈의 말을 믿은 건 다 내 잘못이야
Having you here so late listening to this nonsense
이런 말도 안되는 소리를 듣고 너무 늦게 여기 왔으니
It's not you who should get up
일어나야 할 사람은 당신이 아닙니다
Get up you bastard
일어나라 이 새끼야
Even a bastard like you, the Intelligence Bureau,
너 같은 놈도 정보국은
Or a mental hospital?
아니면 정신병원?
No matter where you are, I will definitely send you there
네가 어디에 있든 반드시 그곳으로 보내줄게
that thing
그 일
Can you give me a look?
좀 봐주실 수 있나요?
So
그래서
you really are
당신은 정말로
My grandson?
내 손자요?
Yes
예
dongzhi
동지
Chairman, what's wrong with you?
위원장님, 무슨 일이세요?
Do you really want to believe that fantasy?
정말 그 환상을 믿고 싶나요?
that
저것
I know this sounds ridiculous
나도 이게 말도 안되는 소리라는 걸 알아
But I bought that watch in a jewelry store yesterday
그런데 어제 보석상에서 그 시계를 샀어요
He said that he finally got a piece from abroad.
드디어 해외에서 작품을 받았다고 하더군요.
I spent a lot of money to buy it for my grandson.
나는 손자를 위해 그것을 사려고 많은 돈을 썼습니다.
And the words engraved on it were written by me.
그리고 거기에 새겨진 문구는 제가 직접 쓴 것입니다.
And the engraving on the back is exactly the same.
그리고 뒷면의 각인도 똑같습니다.
Can I even admit my handwriting is wrong?
내 필체가 틀렸다는 걸 인정할 수 있을까?
where is that watch
그 시계는 어디에 있나요?
Could it be stolen by him?
그 사람이 그것을 훔칠 수도 있나요?
I received it this morning
오늘 아침에 받았어요
But you arrested him last night
하지만 당신은 어젯밤에 그를 체포했어요
I'm confused now too
나도 지금 혼란스러워
When he said he was my grandson
그가 내 손자라고 말했을 때
The weird thing is
이상한 점은
This makes me feel pity for the beauty
미인에 대한 안타까움을 느끼게 되네요
wrong
잘못된
Impossible chairman
불가능한 회장
this is absolutely ridiculous
이건 정말 말도 안 되는 일이야
That guy should be locked up again immediately.
그 사람은 즉시 다시 가둬야 합니다.
Soon Ae
순애
do you recognize me
날 알아 보 겠어
I am Yunying Soon Ae
저는 윤영순애입니다
Soon Ae
순애
Thank you
감사합니다
Yunying
윤잉
Oh Soon Ae
오순애
- Ouch- Mom
- 아야- 엄마
Refreshed yet?
아직 새로 고쳤나요?
sorry
죄송합니다
Why are you apologizing?
왜 사과하는 거야?
It's okay, just wake up
괜찮아 그냥 일어나
never mind
괜찮아요
Soon Ae
순애
Have you seen the prisoner's face?
죄수의 얼굴을 본 적이 있나요?
No
아니요
Does the prisoner live across from your house?
그 죄수는 당신 집 건너편에 살고 있나요?
Teacher Yin Haijun
인하이준 선생님
what do you mean
무슨 뜻이에요
How could the teacher be a criminal?
선생님이 어떻게 범죄자가 될 수 있나요?
That's outrageous
그건 터무니없는 일이야
no
아니요
Thank you for coming back safe and sound
무사히 돌아와주셔서 감사합니다
sorry
죄송합니다
I'm sorry for you
미안해요
right now we
지금 우리는
Do they look like relatives?
친척처럼 보이나요?
It may not look like it
안 그럴 수도 있겠네요
but it doesn't matter
하지만 그건 중요하지 않아
Anyway, I've already said it all
어쨌든 이미 다 말했잖아
But did you come because you knew I was at home?
그런데 내가 집에 있는 걸 알고 오셨나요?
correct
옳은
Soon Ae woke up
곧 애가 일어났어
She told the police
그녀는 경찰에게 말했다
What happened that day
그날 무슨 일이 있었나요
and who saved her
그리고 누가 그녀를 구했는지
Teacher him
선생님
Came to help me
나를 도우러 왔어요
Let's go
갑시다
Really
정말
Yes, I understand
네 이해했습니다
What
무엇
No
아니요
There's nothing suspicious about him
그 사람에 대해선 의심스러운 게 하나도 없어
It is good
좋다
Thank you Dongzhi
동지님 감사합니다
I don't believe what he said
나는 그가 말한 것을 믿지 않는다
It's because you always ask me for help
넌 항상 나에게 도움을 요청하기 때문이야
will let him go temporarily
그를 일시적으로 놓아줄 것이다
But this is not enough
하지만 이것만으로는 충분하지 않습니다
More conclusive evidence is needed
더 결정적인 증거가 필요하다
have you seen it on tv
TV에서 본 적 있어?
That kind of show about finding lost relatives, right?
잃어버린 친척을 찾는 그런 쇼죠?
I heard that I occasionally try to do this
가끔 이런 일을 하려고 한다고 들었는데
It hurts
아파요
It's just a blood draw, nothing more
그냥 피 뽑는 것 뿐이지, 그 이상은 아니야
Don't know what the result will be
결과가 어떻게 될지 모른다
You can't help but know
당신은 도울 수 없지만 알 수 있습니다.
If the result is wrong
결과가 잘못된 경우
I'll send you to the intelligence agency or a mental hospital
정보기관이나 정신병원으로 보내줄게
I see
알겠어요
I let you go because I believed in the chairman.
회장님을 믿었기 때문에 놔줬어요.
It's not that I believe you
내가 당신을 믿는 것이 아닙니다
I don't believe any of your nonsense
나는 당신의 말도 안되는 소리를 믿지 않습니다
So I'll keep an eye on you until the results come out.
그러니까 결과가 나올 때까지 지켜봐야겠습니다.
Don't do anything stupid. Just stay at home.
쓸데없는 짓 하지 말고 그냥 집에 있어.
Not allowed to go to school either
학교에도 갈 수 없다.
I will check at any time, you know?
언제든지 확인해 보겠습니다. 아시죠?
that
저것
Forget it, not that one
잊어버려, 그거 말고
Who did our Hee-seop marry?
우리 희섭이는 누구랑 결혼했어요?
My mother is Lee Soon Ae
우리 엄마는 이순애예요
Lee Soon Ae
이순애
Isn't it from the bus station chamber of commerce?
버스정류장 상공회의소에서 나온 거 아닌가요?
Is Brother Jiongwan his daughter?
종관오빠는 딸인가요?
That's it
그게 다야
So to say
말하자면
Did you know who I was from the beginning?
내가 누구인지 처음부터 알고 있었나요?
I only found out after coming here
여기 오고 나서야 알았어
I had no idea that my father had any relatives or elders
나는 아버지에게 친척이나 연장자가 있는지 전혀 몰랐습니다.
Why
왜
How could you not know me?
어떻게 나를 모를 수 있니?
It seems you have lost contact
연락이 두절된 것 같군요
He didn't tell me anything else about you either.
그 사람도 나한테 너에 대해 아무 말도 안 했어.
Let's go
갑시다
This brat
이 녀석
And he said he didn’t believe it at all
그리고 전혀 믿지 않는다고 하더군요
He looks hurt, right?
그 사람 상처받은 것 같죠?
That is to say
즉 말하자면
I mean, you really weren't hurt, right?
내 말은, 당신은 정말로 다치지 않았다는 거죠, 그렇죠?
Could it be that he was hit somewhere invisible?
혹시 보이지 않는 곳에 부딪힌 것은 아닐까?
Don't let me know
나에게 알리지 마세요
He's not that kind of person
그 사람은 그런 사람이 아니거든요
I'm really scared
정말 무서워요
What could happen to you or go wrong?
당신에게 무슨 일이 일어나거나 잘못될 수 있나요?
I should be more scared
좀 더 겁을 먹었어야 했는데
I'm afraid you'll be in danger because of me
나 때문에 네가 위험해질까 봐
Afraid of messing up everything
모든 것을 망칠까 두려워
Although it seems to have become like this
이렇게 된 것 같으면서도
I will definitely catch the real culprit.
반드시 진범을 잡겠습니다.
I'll make him pay for all the crimes he's committed so far
지금까지 지은 죄값 다 갚게 해줄게
pay the price
대가를 치르다
We are getting closer to this goal
우리는 이 목표에 점점 더 가까워지고 있습니다
Someone who already knows the appearance of the witness
목격자의 모습을 이미 알고 있는 사람
And the police
그리고 경찰은
At least one police officer will be on our side
적어도 한 명의 경찰관이 우리 편이 될 것입니다
On our side?
우리 편?
It doesn't feel like it
그런 느낌은 아닌데
Although it is said to be surveillance
감시라고는 하지만
But he'll help soon
하지만 그 사람이 곧 도와줄 거예요
He has believed half and left the other half
그는 반은 믿고 나머지 반은 버렸느니라
It will be achieved soon
곧 달성되겠죠
How to do
수행하는 방법
Because he is absolutely
왜냐면 그 사람은 절대적으로
You can’t win against someone who can predict the future
미래를 예측하는 사람에겐 이길 수 없어
Wait a moment
잠깐만요
- How much - 100 won
- 얼마 - 100원
What newspaper are you reading?
어떤 신문을 읽고 있나요?
If it were today’s report on June 7
6월 7일 오늘의 보도라면
The headline should be about building a new expressway, right?
헤드라인은 새로운 고속도로 건설에 관한 것이어야 합니다. 그렇죠?
From Daejeon to Jinju
대전에서 진주까지
And Cheongju to Sangju
그리고 청주에서 상주까지
And it seems like this from Cheonan to Nonsan
그리고 천안에서 논산까지는 이런거 같아요
Are you here to spy on me?
나를 염탐하러 왔나요?
The catcher is Kim Dong-ki
포수는 김동기
Runner prepares for first base
주자는 1루를 준비한다
pass touchdown
터치다운 통과
- It's really boring. - Safety on base.
- 정말 지루해요 - 기지의 안전
Not only can I not go out
밖에 나갈 수 없을 뿐만 아니라
The ball flew over the outfield
공이 외야 밖으로 날아갔다.
I even know the result of the game
경기 결과도 알고 있어
So watching football games is boring
그래서 축구 경기를 보는 것은 지루하다
Pintos team 5 points Lions team 4 points
핀토스 팀 5점 라이온스 팀 4점
Team Pintos wins
핀토스 팀 승리
competition is over
경쟁은 끝났다
He is letting his opponent down today
오늘은 상대를 실망시키네요
Yes, if you refer to last year’s competition
네, 작년 대회를 참고로 하면
It will be interesting today
오늘은 재미있겠다
Count the number of matches between two people
두 사람 사이의 일치 횟수 계산
- This is the fifth time - That's right
- 이번이 다섯 번째예요 - 그렇죠
The player with the red belt will win 3-2.
빨간색 벨트를 착용한 플레이어가 3-2로 승리합니다.
Just think you're crazy and trust me for once
미쳤다고 생각하고 한번만 믿어봐
We don't have time to waste like this
우리 이렇게 낭비할 시간 없어
The prisoner who killed three people
세 사람을 죽인 죄수
It's still fair and square now
지금도 여전히 공평하고 공평해요
Feel free to walk outside
마음껏 밖으로 걸어가세요
I shouldn't be here anyway
어차피 난 여기 있어서는 안 됐어
Even if I catch the culprit
범인을 잡아도
I can't deal with him either
나도 그 사람을 상대할 수 없어
In the end, it's up to you as a detective to settle the matter.
결국 문제를 해결하는 것은 형사인 당신에게 달려 있습니다.
I will share the information I have with you
제가 가지고 있는 정보를 여러분께 공유하겠습니다.
from now on
지금부터
Let's work together
같이 일하자
Are you saying that Go Mi-sook is lying?
고미숙 씨가 거짓말을 하고 있다는 겁니까?
She didn't report the real culprit
그녀는 진짜 범인을 신고하지 않았다
Instead, they put the blame on Gao Minxiu.
대신 그들은 Gao Minxiu를 비난했습니다.
Although Gao Minxiu is indeed suspicious
가오민슈는 정말 의심스럽긴 하지만
But I didn’t expect Gao Meishu to treat her family
하지만 Gao Meishu가 그녀의 가족을 대할 것이라고는 기대하지 않았습니다
Although I’m not qualified to say that
내가 그런 말을 할 자격은 없지만
You just did that because you wanted to catch the prisoner.
당신은 죄수를 잡고 싶어서 그렇게 한 것뿐입니다.
If the real culprit is a family member
진짜 범인이 가족이라면
Even his family must let him make atonement for his sins
그의 가족이라도 그의 죄를 속죄하게 해야 한다
I know when Baek Hee-seop and Baek Yoo-seop were hospitalized
백희섭과 백유섭이 언제 입원했는지 알아요
have you been to the hospital
병원에 가봤어?
sorry nurse
죄송해요 간호사
Hello
안녕하세요
Could you please pass it on?
전달해 주시겠어요?
According to the original development
원래 개발에 따르면
Things will be even worse for both of them than they are now.
두 사람의 상황은 지금보다 훨씬 더 나빠질 것입니다.
What will happen to Baek Hee-seop because of his brother?
형 때문에 백희섭에게 무슨 일이 일어날까?
Live resenting yourself and others
자신과 남을 원망하며 살아라
And you will live in guilt for the rest of your life
그리고 넌 평생 죄책감 속에 살게 될 거야
Maybe handle this case properly
어쩌면 이 사건을 제대로 처리할 수도 있겠네요
will be an opportunity to change your future
당신의 미래를 바꿀 수 있는 기회가 될 것입니다
Of course me too
물론 나도
so what you mean is
그래서 당신이 말하는 것은
Let's work together?
같이 일하자?
Although we have to wait for the results to come out
결과가 나올 때까지 기다려야 하지만
to know if you are crazy
당신이 미쳤는지 알기 위해
But is it because I always come into contact with you?
그런데 내가 늘 연락을 해서 그런 걸까?
Why do I feel like I'm crazy too?
왜 나도 미친 것 같은 느낌이 들까?
So
그래서
Just go and see Gao Mi-sook first, okay?
그냥 가오미숙 먼저 만나러 가, 알았지?
It seems like his dad can still be of help here.
여기서는 그의 아버지가 여전히 도움이 될 수 있을 것 같습니다.
Wait, Yanyu doesn’t know yet.
잠깐, Yanyu는 아직 모릅니다.
Dongsik, is that you?
동식아, 너야?
Why are you here so late?
왜 이렇게 늦게 왔나요?
This is Dong-sik
동식이에요
Can Teacher Yin go out with me?
인 선생님이 저랑 데이트할 수 있나요?
But
하지만
I'll take care of you, Dong-sik
내가 챙겨줄게 동식아
Detective Bai also said that I must not go out.
바이 형사도 나가면 안 된다고 하더군요.
I promised him I'd be with you.
나는 그에게 당신과 함께하겠다고 약속했습니다.
After all, I have a pretty high level of integrity.
결국, 나는 꽤 높은 수준의 성실성을 가지고 있습니다.
Not grandpa
할아버지 아님
Why are you so surprised?
왜 그렇게 놀랐나요?
I'm rather embarrassed
오히려 부끄러워
Shouldn't you be used to it by now?
이제 익숙해져야 하지 않겠습니까?
If I say "Haejun"
내가 '해준'이라고 말하면
Just say "it's grandpa"
그냥 "할아버지예요"라고 말해요
Oops
이런
this mood
이 기분
It's really strange
정말 이상해요
Now that it’s all mentioned, let’s try this
이제 모든 내용이 언급되었으므로 시도해 보겠습니다.
- Please drink - Okay
- 마셔주세요 - 알았어
I've always imagined
난 항상 상상해왔어
Have a drink with the grandson
손자와 함께 한잔
You accepted the report even before it came out?
보고서가 나오기도 전에 보고서를 받아들였나요?
That kind of thing is for others to see.
그런 일은 다른 사람들이 보기에 그렇습니다.
Would I not recognize my own grandson?
내 손자를 알아보지 못할까요?
We get along so well
우리는 너무 잘 지내요
Show me your watch
시계를 보여주세요
hurry up
서둘러요
I'm here
나는 여기 있다
I have handwritten words engraved on it to give to you.
당신에게 드리고자 손으로 쓴 문구를 새겼습니다.
"Time flies, love still exists"
"시간은 흘러도 사랑은 여전히 ​​존재한다"
do you know what this means
이게 무슨 뜻인지 알아?
Time flies but love lasts forever
시간은 흐르지만 사랑은 영원하다
You really understand
정말 이해하시네요
By the way, why did you carve this? It’s so disgusting.
그런데 이건 왜 조각한 걸까요? 너무 역겨워요.
Yeah
응
I just want to say
나는 단지 말하고 싶다
It will feel better to see it when you are tired
피곤할 때 보면 더 좋을 것 같아요
I will think of "Grandpa loves me very much"
'할아버지가 나를 정말 사랑하신다'고 생각하겠습니다.
"I've been looking forward to meeting me since I was born"
"태어날 때부터 만나고 싶었어요"
“He even bought this watch as a gift to me.”
“그는 나에게 선물로 이 시계를 사주기도 했어요.”
Even if time passes
시간이 지나도
One day I left this world
어느 날 나는 이 세상을 떠났습니다.
I also hope that I love you
나도 당신을 사랑하기를 바랍니다
Lasts 100 years 200 years
100년 200년 지속
I can always protect you with this kind of heart.
이런 마음으로 늘 지켜드릴 수 있어요.
By the way, who is Yeonwoo’s other half?
그런데 연우의 반쪽은 누구일까요?
So you're talking about Qing'e from Fengfeng Tea House
그럼 Fengfeng Tea House의 Qing'e에 대해 말씀하시는 건가요?
She is your mother, my daughter-in-law
그 사람은 네 엄마, 내 며느리야
real or fake
진실 혹은 거짓
No matter it's true or false, just leave me
그것이 사실이든 거짓이든 상관없이 그냥 나를 떠나세요
Go well
잘되 가다
Hey wait, this is it
잠깐만, 이게 다야
your mother is right here
네 엄마는 바로 여기 있어
keep your voice down
목소리를 낮추세요
It's okay. Let's go up there.
괜찮아 저기 올라가자
Go in
들어가다
and my grandpa
그리고 우리 할아버지
Go and see what your mother is up to now
가서 네 엄마가 지금 뭐하고 있는지 좀 봐라
Hey, what are you looking at?
야, 뭘 보고 있는 거야?
Why don't you go home quickly?
빨리 집에 가는 게 어때?
Let's go
갑시다
- Take a good walk - I have to go check it out.
- 잘 산책하세요 - 가서 확인해야 해요.
Grandpa said everything he said, so he spoke smoothly.
할아버지는 할 말을 다 해주셔서 유창하게 말을 하더군요.
Damn grandpa
빌어먹을 할아버지
Oops
이런
Please drink less wine
와인을 적게 마셔주세요
You will have a hard time with high blood pressure in the future
앞으로 고혈압으로 고생하실 거에요.
Oops
이런
Turns out I’m the damn grandpa
알고보니 내가 그 빌어먹을 할아버지였어
How dare
어떻게 감히
my precious grandson
내 소중한 손자
congratulations
축하해요
All meals are free today
오늘은 모든 식사가 무료입니다.
Because you are the 20,000th guest at Fengfeng Tea House
당신은 Fengfeng Tea House의 20,000번째 손님이니까요.
What a joke
좋은 농담 이었어
I was serious
나는 진지했다
I know you want me to stop talking to you
내가 너랑 그만 얘기하길 바라는 거 알아
Don’t recommend meals to you either
너한테도 식사 추천하지마
But now that you have become the 20,000th guest
그런데 이제 20,000번째 손님이 되셨으니
I won't give in this time
이번엔 포기하지 않을 거야
Sit down and I'll prepare some tea for you
앉으세요. 제가 차를 준비하겠습니다.
why are you sitting down
왜 앉아있어?
You are the 20,000th guest
당신은 20,000번째 손님입니다
I want to use this as an excuse to talk to you.
나는 이것을 핑계로 당신과 이야기하고 싶습니다.
Mr. Yin Haijun
인하이준 씨
There are so many names, why is it Haejun?
이름이 이렇게 많은데 왜 해준인가요?
Did your boyfriend tell you my name?
네 남자친구가 내 이름을 알려줬어?
Last time
마지막으로
Why did you look at me like that when we met in front of the theater?
극장 앞에서 만났을 때 왜 나를 그렇게 쳐다봤나요?
Which kind
어떤 종류
Then he treated me like air and kept ignoring me
그러다가 날 공기처럼 대하고 계속 무시했지
are you questioning me
나한테 질문하는 거야?
That's not true
그건 사실이 아니야
I should drink more good stuff but I just can’t.
좋은 걸 더 많이 마셔야 하는데 그럴 수가 없어요.
This is my tenth cup of Shuanghe tea
이것이 내 솽허차 열 번째 잔이다
Why can't I drink
나는 왜 술을 못마시나?
Because it’s the last drink
마지막 잔이니까
you are the last guest
당신이 마지막 손님이에요
“The last guest”
“마지막 손님”
I plan to close this cafe
나는 이 카페를 닫을 계획이야
leave this village
이 마을을 떠나라
Do you want to leave this village?
이 마을을 떠나고 싶나요?
Yeonwoo, I mean
연우야, 내 말은
your boyfriend
당신의 남자 친구
does he know
그는 알고 있나요
Of course I don't know
물론 나는 모른다
I only tell you one person
딱 한 사람한테만 말해줄게
why me
왜 나야
have no idea
전혀 모른다
Maybe you're meant to hear this from me.
어쩌면 당신은 나에게서 이 말을 듣게 될지도 모릅니다.
That's why I happened to appear here
그래서 내가 여기 나타나게 된 거야
You can almost predict the time when I'm going to let go.
내가 놓아줄 시간은 거의 예측할 수 있다.
why do you want to leave
왜 떠나고 싶어?
Want to know in detail
자세히 알고싶다
You should have gotten to know me earlier.
당신은 나를 더 일찍 알았어야 했어요.
it's too late
너무 늦었어
It's time for me to prepare
이제 준비할 시간이에요
Why are you leaving so soon?
왜 이렇게 빨리 떠나는 거야?
Brother, when did you come back?
형님, 언제 돌아오셨나요?
Just came back
방금 돌아왔어
It's getting late
늦겠다
Really? I was so focused that I didn't notice the time.
정말요? 너무 집중해서 시간 가는 줄도 몰랐어요.
And someone forgot to make toast for me again
그리고 누군가 또 나를 위해 건배 만드는 것을 잊어버렸어요
Sorry you didn't have dinner
미안, 저녁을 안 먹었어?
No
아니요
Being full hinders my thinking
배가 부르면 생각하는 데 방해가 된다
Suffer it now
이제 고생해라
Misunderstood
오해
I heard you saved people
네가 사람을 구했다고 들었어
It turns out you are indeed a good person
알고보니 당신은 정말 좋은 사람이군요
I didn't even know I would treat you like that
내가 당신을 그렇게 대할 줄은 몰랐어요
Oops, it’s time to find my girlfriend
앗, 이제 여자친구를 찾을 시간이에요
Are you going to find your girlfriend now?
이제 여자친구를 찾으러 가시나요?
Yes, I've been staying here recently.
네, 최근에 여기 묵었어요.
Not able to meet often
자주 만나지 못함
Maybe she was a little awkward because of this
아마 이 때문에 좀 어색했을지도 몰라
I need to make up for it quickly.
빨리 만회해야 해요.
Okay, save the toast for next time
알겠습니다. 토스트는 다음 시간을 위해 아껴두세요
Did you see your girlfriend yesterday?
어제 여자친구 봤어?
Yes, I haven’t had a good date in a long time.
네, 오랜만에 좋은 데이트를 못 했어요.
Yeah
응
Nothing happened, right?
아무 일도 일어나지 않았죠?
As usual, what's wrong?
평소처럼, 무슨 일이야?
should something happen?
무슨 일이 일어나야 할까?
Not just a casual question
단순한 질문이 아닌
What are you asking this weird question?
이 이상한 질문은 무엇입니까?
- Here you go - Thank you
- 여기요 - 감사합니다
There are really many
정말 많아요
That's right, why bother sending so many things?
그렇죠, 왜 그렇게 많은 것을 보내려고 애쓰시나요?
I'm very well
난 아주 잘 해요
I want to use this to bring you some comfort.
나는 이것을 당신에게 위안을 주기 위해 사용하고 싶습니다.
Hope you get over the bad and get back on your feet again
나쁜 점을 극복하고 다시 일어설 수 있기를 바랍니다.
do you feel better now
지금 기분이 나아 졌니
much better
훨씬 낫다
correct
옳은
I heard that you were misunderstood because of me
나 때문에 네가 오해를 받았다고 들었어
Suffered a lot
고생많았어
I should have caught the criminal earlier, sorry Soon Ae
진작에 범인을 잡았어야 했는데 미안 순애야
don't say that
그런 말 하지 마
If it weren't for my teacher, I would have been kidnapped by the criminals long ago
선생님이 아니었다면 나는 오래전에 범죄자들에게 납치되었을 것입니다.
On that dark and scary road
어둡고 무서운 그 길에서
When I see the teacher
선생님을 만나면
At that moment I felt "saved"
그 순간 나는 '구원됐다'는 느낌을 받았다.
Makes me feel more at ease
좀 더 마음이 편해지는 것 같아요
By the way, why are you going out?
그런데 왜 밖에 나가나요?
You can go out now
이제 나가도 돼
It seems like there are a lot of people coming to visit me.
저를 찾아오시는 분들이 많이 오시는 것 같더라고요.
Yes, many people from the village came
네, 마을 사람들이 많이 왔어요
You also know the character of our head teacher
우리 교장 선생님 성격도 아시잖아요
Bring a group of classmates over every night
매일 밤 한 무리의 친구들을 집으로 데려오세요
It's so noisy
너무 시끄러워요
Not to mention the quiet recuperation is simply not peaceful.
조용한 요양은 말할 것도 없이 평화롭지 않습니다.
How long has this thing been sitting here?
이게 얼마나 오랫동안 여기 앉아 있었나요?
The prisoner has been here before
죄수는 전에 여기에 와본 적이 있어요
Maybe it was to obliterate the traces left by his mistake
아마도 자신의 실수로 남겨진 흔적을 지우기 위해서였을 것이다.